[Sharp Blade in the Snow]
[نصل حاد في الثلج]
[Episode 16]
[الحلقة 16]
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
why are you barefoot again?
لماذا أنت حافي القدمين مرة أخرى؟
It's you.
أنت هو.
Who did you think it was?
من كنت تظن أنه؟
You won't feel any remorse
لن تشعر بأي ندم
for executing Yun Zhan,
لتنفيذ حكم الإعدام على يون زان،
the assassin
القاتل
who's been lurking by your side all this time?
من كان يتربص بجانبك طوال هذا الوقت؟
Don't talk nonsense.
لا تتفوه بالهراء.
I'm only unsettled
أنا فقط أشعر بعدم الارتياح
about the decision
بشأن القرار
I have to make tomorrow.
يجب أن أحرص على القيام بذلك غداً.
The Spirit Lord committed a grave offense,
ارتكب الرب الروحي ذنباً جسيماً.
and Xiqi is closing in on us.
وشيقي تقترب منا.
She is also
وهي أيضاً
of your own blood,
من دمك،
and she still holds
وما زالت متمسكة
the Tiger Tally of the Imperial Guard left behind by her late mother.
تعداد النمور للحرس الإمبراطوري الذي تركته والدتها الراحلة.
No matter how this is handled,
بغض النظر عن كيفية التعامل مع هذا الأمر،
it puts us in an impossible position.
هذا يضعنا في موقف مستحيل.
Bai,
نعم،
you don't need to bring
لست بحاجة إلى إحضار
the mung bean cakes anymore.
لم تعد كعكات الفاصوليا الخضراء متوفرة.
Your Majesty, have you grown tired of them?
يا صاحب الجلالة، هل مللت منهم؟
Then I'll change the ingredients tomorrow.
سأغير المكونات غداً.
How about yam?
ماذا عن اليام؟
Bai,
نعم،
the road ahead is dangerous.
الطريق أمامنا خطير.
You have a bright future.
لديك مستقبل مشرق.
I don't want to pull you any deeper into this.
لا أريد أن أزيد الأمر تعقيداً بالنسبة لك.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
I'm not afraid.
أنا لست خائفا.
As long as you're willing,
طالما أنك مستعد،
I beg you to decree our marriage.
أرجوكم أن تقروا زواجنا.
I'm not doing this for myself alone.
أنا لا أفعل هذا من أجل نفسي فقط.
The entire Bai clan
عشيرة باي بأكملها
will stand behind you,
سأقف خلفك،
ready to
جاهز لـ
live and die with you.
أعيش وأموت معك.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Watch out!
انتبه!
Get away!
ابتعد!
Don't touch me with your filthy hands.
لا تلمسني بيديك القذرتين.
Just got kicked out by the Queen,
طردتني الملكة للتو.
now you're throwing a tantrum?
والآن أنت تثور غضباً؟
You dare eavesdrop out here?
أتجرؤ على التجسس هنا؟
I serve the Queen.
أنا أخدم الملكة.
I belong in her hall.
مكاني في قاعتها.
Isn't that exactly where I should be?
أليس هذا هو المكان الذي يجب أن أكون فيه بالضبط؟
Filth like you doesn't deserve to be here.
أمثالك من القذارة لا يستحقون التواجد هنا.
Filth?
رجس؟
The Queen happens to
الملكة تصادف أنها
like filth like us.
مثل القذارة مثلنا.
If you were humble enough to ask,
لو كنت متواضعاً بما يكفي لتسأل،
I might even share a few tricks.
بل قد أشارككم بعض الحيل.
At least
على الأقل
then you'd still have a place
عندها سيظل لديك مكان
serving in the Queen's chambers, wouldn't you?
أليس كذلك؟ ستعمل في غرف الملكة.
You!
أنت!
Since when did a low slave like you
منذ متى أصبح عبدٌ وضيعٌ مثلك...
get to humiliate me?
هل يحق لك إذلالي؟
The bond between Li and me
الرابطة بين لي وأنا
is none of your business!
هذا ليس من شأنك!
Please stop, Mr. Bai!
من فضلك توقف يا سيد باي!
I really
أنا حقاً
didn't see anything.
لم أرَ شيئاً.
I didn't hear anything either.
لم أسمع شيئاً أيضاً.
No.
لا.
You saw it.
لقد رأيت ذلك.
Those eyes of yours
تلك العيون
are far too sharp.
حادة للغاية.
The auspicious time has arrived.
لقد حان الوقت الميمون.
If the noble lady from Mocheng meant for this marriage alliance
إذا كانت السيدة النبيلة من موتشنغ تقصد هذا التحالف الزوجي
still hasn't appeared,
لم يظهر بعد،
then we'll be taking our leave.
ثم سنغادر.
And we'll report to the Young Master of Xiqi
وسنقدم تقريرنا إلى السيد الشاب لشي تشي
that Mocheng
ذلك في المدينة
looks down on our land.
ينظر بازدراء إلى أرضنا.
What should we do now?
ماذا يجب أن نفعل الآن؟
Prime Minister Bai.
رئيس الوزراء باي.
Wait a little longer.
انتظر قليلاً.
Go check the Fengling Palace
اذهب لزيارة قصر فينغلينغ
and the Fengxi Palace.
وقصر فينغشي.
Yes.
نعم.
So this is how Mocheng treats its guests.
هكذا يعامل موتشنغ ضيوفه.
Such humiliation and neglect.
هذا الإذلال والإهمال.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Stop!
قف!
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحية طيبة يا صاحب الجلالة.
I will go to Xiqi myself
سأذهب إلى شيقي بنفسي
and marry the young lord.
وتتزوج من السيد الشاب.
What?
ماذا؟
Can this work?
هل هذا ممكن؟
Xiqi insists on a marriage alliance.
يصر شي تشي على تحالف زواج.
The bride
العروس
must be an eligible woman of the Feng clan.
يجب أن تكون امرأة مؤهلة من عشيرة فينغ.
There's no rule
لا توجد قاعدة
that says the Queen can't be one.
وهذا يعني أن الملكة لا يمكن أن تكون واحدة منهم.
Ridiculous!
سخيف!
What?
ماذا؟
Do you think the Young Master
هل تعتقد أن السيد الشاب
is beneath me?
هل هذا أقل من مستواي؟
You already keep 3,000 slaves.
أنت تحتفظ بالفعل بـ 3000 عبد.
How could you possibly join Xiqi
كيف يمكنك الانضمام إلى شيقي؟
and become a lady of our court?
وتصبح سيدة من سيدات بلاطنا؟
You're mistaken.
أنت مخطئ.
This is indeed a marriage alliance,
هذا في الواقع تحالف زواج.
but
لكن
but it will be forged on Mocheng's terms.
لكن سيتم صياغتها وفقًا لشروط موتشينغ.
I've heard the Young Master of Xiqi
لقد سمعت عن السيد الشاب لشي تشي
kills without mercy,
يقتل بلا رحمة،
leaving rivers of blood wherever he goes.
يترك أنهاراً من الدماء أينما ذهب.
That sounds like a perfect match for me.
يبدو ذلك مناسباً تماماً لي.
Those are nothing more than rumors from the Central Plains.
هذه ليست سوى شائعات من السهول الوسطى.
Whether they're true or not doesn't concern me.
سواء كانت صحيحة أم لا، فهذا لا يهمني.
Today,
اليوم،
I will personally see this alliance fulfilled.
سأحرص شخصياً على إتمام هذا التحالف.
This...
هذا...
How can this be acceptable?
كيف يمكن قبول هذا؟
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
Xiqi is a barbarous land.
شي تشي أرض همجية.
How can you possibly take such a risk?
كيف يمكنك أن تخاطر بمثل هذه المخاطرة؟
The Phoenix Seal
ختم العنقاء
will remain with Prime Minister Bai for now.
سيبقى مع رئيس الوزراء باي في الوقت الحالي.
If I have not returned within half a month,
إذا لم أعد خلال نصف شهر،
Prime Minister Bai may use this seal
قد يستخدم رئيس الوزراء باي هذا الختم
to convene the court
لعقد جلسة المحكمة
and choose a new sovereign.
واختاروا حاكماً جديداً.
I'm going to Xiqi
سأذهب إلى شي تشي
to demand an answer
للمطالبة بإجابة
for Mocheng's late ruler.
تكريماً لحاكم موتشنغ الراحل.
So you
إذن أنت
truly leave yourself no way back?
هل حقاً لا تترك لنفسك أي سبيل للعودة؟
There has never been a way back in this world.
لم يكن هناك سبيل للعودة في هذا العالم.
The Phoenix Incense formula
تركيبة بخور فينيكس
is still missing a crucial catalyst.
لا يزال يفتقر إلى عامل محفز حاسم.
I've heard
لقد سمعت
a black jade mine was recently discovered in southern Xiqi.
تم اكتشاف منجم لليشم الأسود مؤخراً في جنوب شيتشي.
In half a month,
في غضون نصف شهر،
I will return to Mocheng
سأعود إلى موتشنغ
with the Young Master of Xiqi
مع السيد الشاب لشي تشي
and the dowry.
والمهر.
May you remain safe
نسأل الله أن يحفظكم سالمين
and return soon.
وسنعود قريباً.
We respectfully see Your Majesty off.
نودع جلالتكم بكل احترام.
Come, drink.
هيا، اشرب.
Look, what's that?
انظر، ما هذا؟
Someone's on the horse.
أحدهم يمتطي الحصان.
Be careful.
احرص.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
It's His Highness.
إنه صاحب السمو.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Hurry!
عجل!
General Lu.
الجنرال لو.
General Lu,
الجنرال لو،
His Highness is back.
لقد عاد صاحب السمو.
Your Highness, you've finally returned.
صاحب السمو، لقد عدت أخيراً.
We were worried sick.
كنا قلقين للغاية.
That Demon Lord
ذلك سيد الشياطين
has tortured you into such a state.
لقد عذبك حتى وصلت إلى هذه الحالة.
I failed to rescue you.
لقد فشلت في إنقاذك.
Please punish me.
أرجوكم عاقبوني.
General Lu,
الجنرال لو،
that's too harsh.
هذا قاسٍ للغاية.
Please rise.
يرجى الوقوف.
Now
الآن
there's an important matter
هناك أمر مهم
that needs your preparation.
هذا يتطلب استعدادك.
Please give your orders, Your Highness.
تفضل بإصدار أوامرك يا صاحب السمو.
That Demon Lord
ذلك سيد الشياطين
will depart from the old southwestern isles,
ستغادر من الجزر الجنوبية الغربية القديمة،
cross the border a day from now,
اعبر الحدود بعد يوم من الآن،
and within three days
وفي غضون ثلاثة أيام
will pass through
سوف يمر
the woods near Luo­wu Bridge.
الغابة القريبة من جسر لوو وو.
Our chance to strike has come.
لقد حانت فرصتنا للهجوم.
Indeed, this is a rare opportunity.
في الواقع، هذه فرصة نادرة.
We must eliminate her in one strike.
يجب أن نقضي عليها بضربة واحدة.
She was responsible for the fall of Dongli,
كانت هي المسؤولة عن سقوط دونغلي،
and now she dares seek an alliance with Xiqi.
والآن تجرؤ على السعي إلى التحالف مع شيكي.
She's heartless.
إنها عديمة الرحمة.
She should have been killed long ago.
كان ينبغي قتلها منذ زمن طويل.
Kill her!
اقتلها!
The Queen of Mocheng was never decent to begin with.
لم تكن ملكة موتشينغ لائقة في الأصل.
She dares to come to Xiqi herself
تجرأت على المجيء إلى شي تشي بنفسها
with such shameless audacity.
بمثل هذه الجرأة الوقحة.
Now it's us she's put in an impossible position.
الآن نحن من وضعناها في موقف لا يُطاق.
But the Queen of Mocheng
لكن ملكة موتشنغ
is indeed
هو كذلك بالفعل
an unmarried woman of the Feng clan.
امرأة غير متزوجة من عشيرة فينغ.
Xiqi can hardly go back on its word in public.
من الصعب على شركة Xiqi أن تتراجع عن كلمتها علنًا.
A so-called royal marriage.
زواج ملكي مزعوم.
No dowry, no political backing.
لا مهر، ولا دعم سياسي.
She's worth less than even Feng Ling'er, just a minor member of the clan.
قيمتها أقل حتى من قيمة فينغ لينغ إير، وهي مجرد عضو ثانوي في العشيرة.
I've come here
لقد أتيت إلى هنا
to form an alliance through marriage
لتكوين تحالف من خلال الزواج
with your Young Master
مع سيدك الشاب
and
و
to plot greater designs together.
للتخطيط لتصاميم أكبر معاً.
I am the Queen of a country.
أنا ملكة دولة.
Since I've personally entered Xiqi to claim the marriage,
بما أنني دخلت شخصياً إلى شيقي للمطالبة بالزواج،
it means I am here to take your Young Master as my consort.
هذا يعني أنني هنا لأتخذ سيدك الشاب قريناً لي.
Please hurry back and report.
يرجى العودة سريعاً وإبلاغنا بالنتائج.
Tell him
أخبره
to prepare his dowry and belongings
لتجهيز مهره وممتلكاته
and marry into Mocheng.
والزواج من عائلة موشينغ.
I spare your life
أعفو عنك من الحياة
only because you are an envoy.
فقط لأنك مبعوث.
But if another word of disrespect
لكن إذا كانت كلمة أخرى من عدم الاحترام
reaches my ears
يصل إلى أذني
we'll see whether my future husband
سنرى ما إذا كان زوجي المستقبلي
is willing to spare yours.
مستعد للتضحية بك.
Send word immediately.
أرسل الخبر فوراً.
Tell Young Master to prepare.
أخبر السيد الشاب أن يستعد.
Yes.
نعم.
The journey to Xiqi
الرحلة إلى شي تشي
is uncertain, and danger lies ahead.
الوضع غير مؤكد، والخطر يتربص بنا.
For Mocheng,
بالنسبة لموتشنغ،
I have no choice but to stake everything on this gamble.
ليس لدي خيار سوى المراهنة بكل شيء في هذه المقامرة.
I only hope mother
أتمنى فقط أن تكون أمي
will bless me to survive this ordeal.
أتمنى أن يوفقني الله للنجاة من هذه المحنة.
I suppose by now
أظن أن الأمر قد أصبح واضحاً الآن
he should be safe.
ينبغي أن يكون بأمان.
Mr. Bai, please take a rest.
السيد باي، تفضل بالراحة.
Your mother is here to see you.
والدتك هنا لرؤيتك.
Mother, you came just in time.
يا أمي، لقد أتيتِ في الوقت المناسب تماماً.
Please help me see
أرجو مساعدتي على الرؤية
if the Queen would like these pastries.
إذا كانت الملكة ترغب في هذه المعجنات.
She's grown tired of
لقد سئمت من
the osmanthus mung-bean cakes she usually eats.
كعكات الفاصوليا الخضراء المزينة بزهرة الأوسمانثوس التي تتناولها عادةً.
These are all new recipes I've made.
هذه كلها وصفات جديدة قمت بإعدادها.
When she returns,
عندما تعود،
I want her to try something new.
أريدها أن تجرب شيئاً جديداً.
How much longer are you going to busy yourself
إلى متى ستظل مشغولاً؟
with these useless things?
بهذه الأشياء عديمة الفائدة؟
The Queen's trip this time…
رحلة الملكة هذه المرة؟
I fear
أخشى
she may never return.
ربما لن تعود أبداً.
She said it herself.
قالت ذلك بنفسها.
She said my mung-bean cakes were her favorite.
قالت إن كعكات الفاصوليا الخضراء التي أعددتها كانت المفضلة لديها.
She said she would come back.
قالت إنها ستعود.
She is the Queen.
إنها الملكة.
She won't break her promise.
لن تخلف وعدها.
Come back?
عد؟
Do you even know
هل تعلم حتى؟
what kind of savage land Xiqi is?
ما نوع الأرض المتوحشة التي تمثلها شي تشي؟
And that Young Master of theirs
وذلك السيد الشاب خاصتهم
is infamous for his brutality.
يشتهر بوحشيته.
Even if the Queen returns alive,
حتى لو عادت الملكة على قيد الحياة،
the title of future consort
لقب القرين المستقبلي
will belong to that Xiqi barbarian.
سيؤول ذلك إلى ذلك البربري شيقي.
What are you still clinging to?
بماذا ما زلت تتمسك به؟
By the Queen's side,
بجانب الملكة،
you'll have no place there.
لن يكون لك مكان هناك.
Must my son
يجب على ابني
be destined to nothing more than a secondary consort?
هل سيُكتب لها أن تكون مجرد قرينة ثانوية؟
I don't care!
لا أهتم!
As long as she comes back…
طالما أنها ستعود؟
As long as I can see her,
طالما أستطيع رؤيتها،
I'm willing.
أنا مستعد.
I'm willing to be a consort.
أنا على استعداد لأن أكون قرينة.
Yu,
يو،
let it go.
دع الأمر يمر.
If she doesn't return,
إذا لم تعد،
at worst,
في أسوأ الأحوال،
I'll go to Xiqi to find her myself.
سأذهب إلى شيكي لأجدها بنفسي.
Young master.
سيد شاب.
Keep an eye on the young master.
راقبوا السيد الشاب.
Without my orders,
بدون أوامري،
he is not to leave the mansion at all.
ممنوع عليه مغادرة القصر على الإطلاق.
Whoever kills the Demon Lord
من يقتل سيد الشياطين
will be richly rewarded.
سيُكافأون بسخاء.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
what are you waiting for?
ماذا تنتظر؟
Your Highness!
يا صاحب السمو!